<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Nomad Rides</title>
  <subtitle>Meet other nomads &amp; travel together</subtitle>
  <id>http://nomadrides.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://nomadrides.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://nomadrides.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Cecile Veneziani</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Brussels (13 may - 16 may)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-05-13-brussels.html"/>
    <id>http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-05-13-brussels.html</id>
    <published>2015-05-13T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-19T12:42:08+02:00</updated>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was so close from my place that it only took me 30 min train to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, Brussels, Belgium!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was so close from my place that it only took me 30 min train to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, Brussels, Belgium!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="brussels"&gt;Brussels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm currently one of the teachers at &lt;a href="http://lewagon.org/"&gt;Le Wagon Paris&lt;/a&gt; - a 9 weeks boot camp teaching Ruby and Ruby on Rails to entrepreneurs. Last February, they launched &lt;a href="http://lewagon.org/brussels"&gt;Le Wagon Brussels&lt;/a&gt;. In May they started the second batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I taught, why not visiting them and do some tourism in Brussels? Such a nice plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="l-blog-image--centered"&gt;&lt;img alt="Music Instruments Museum, Brussels" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-05-13-brussels/IMG_20150516_182825-b6f14ee8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="another-4-days-abroad"&gt;Another 4 days abroad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-1-2---le-wagon--co-station"&gt;Day 1-2 - Le Wagon / Co-Station&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed in &lt;a href="http://www.co-station.com/"&gt;Co-Station&lt;/a&gt;, a massive 3000 m2 coworking space near by the central railway station, in the heart of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived just on time for the classmates picture. Also got lucky, it was the first day for Lien as teacher. There's not that much girls in IT so it's quite a thing to have a woman as teacher in Paris and in Brussels!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staff and students are really nice. It was pleasant to meet them and work from their space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Wagon Brussels at Co-Station" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-05-13-brussels/IMG_20150513_103030-c16034c7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Wagon Brussels at Co-Station" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-05-13-brussels/IMG_20150514_170617-5b0cfb89.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-3-4---visiting"&gt;Day 3-4 - Visiting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to visit the city by walking across neighborhoods from the city center to Etterbeek, passing by Ixelles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also visited two small museums. First one was the &lt;a href="http://www.hortamuseum.be/"&gt;Horta house&lt;/a&gt; and the second one was the &lt;a href="http://choco-story-brussels.be/"&gt;Chocolate museum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the opportunity of being in Brussels to join the &lt;a href="http://brug.be/"&gt;Belgian Ruby community&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href="http://rubyburgers.co/"&gt;Ruby Burgers&lt;/a&gt; party. That was a nice meet up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Horta House" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-05-13-brussels/IMG_20150516_144952-91f47ddb.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-ive-learned"&gt;What I've learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd say that Brussels is an international city. There're so much nationalities, it's amazing. You can either take subways/trams or just walk along the streets and see where you'll arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, people are easy going and for sure the beer is good. There're good bars where to crash near Flagey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="by-the-way-did-you-know"&gt;By the way, did you know…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…that Flagey is in fact a place? I used to listen to Musiq3 for years. This is a radio from Brussels that broadcasts classic music. Every year they organize the Flagey Festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always taught it was a festival taking place in a charming small village called Flagey. It was quite a shock when I discovered that Flagey is a famous place in Ixelles where people like to go for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Flagey place, Brussels" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-05-13-brussels/IMG_20150516_191019-d06f064a.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-next"&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next batch, I'll try a one week trip to Holland with a coworker from Lille, France.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Cecile Veneziani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Poland (11 Mar - 16 Mar)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-03-11-poland.html"/>
    <id>http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-03-11-poland.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-19T12:42:08+02:00</updated>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Second journey and a brand new adventure. This time, a friend joined me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's meet Thomas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Second journey and a brand new adventure. This time, a friend joined me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's meet Thomas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thomas"&gt;Thomas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born in Paris in 1984, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aryko"&gt;Thomas&lt;/a&gt; is now a full packed Chti living in Lille, France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-poland"&gt;Why Poland?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to Poland for a special occasion. We attended a Ruby conference. In fact one of the best Ruby conference in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as we're really lucky. It turns out that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkonikowski"&gt;Mateusz&lt;/a&gt;, one of our ex-coworker, is living in Warsaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mateusz &amp;amp; Thomas" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-03-11-poland/IMG_20150316_170629-a36e60aa.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="days-in-warsaw--wroclaw"&gt;5 days in Warsaw / Wroclaw&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let's go! We'd visited him in Warsaw and then went to Wroclaw for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-1-visiting-warsaw"&gt;Day 1: Visiting Warsaw&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent our first day in Poland visiting the city. Fortunately, that was a sunny day. We visited the old town and went back by foot to the city center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the afternoon, we visited the insurrection museum and spent the evening with our friend.
What a great day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Visiting Warsaw" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-03-11-poland/IMG_20150312_111306-efd3e440.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-2-4-conference-in-wroclaw"&gt;Day 2-4: Conference in Wroclaw&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn't have much time to visit Wroclaw. I already visited the city so it didn't bothered me. Anyway, the &lt;a href="http://wrocloverb.com/"&gt;wroc_love.rb conference&lt;/a&gt; was really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Attending Wroclove.rb" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-03-11-poland/CAClre9WcAAGz76-c057c2d7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-5-working-from-foap-in-warsaw"&gt;Day 5: Working from Foap in Warsaw&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Warsaw for our last day, we decided to work from there. We didn't have the opportunity to look for a coworking space. &lt;a href="https://foap.com/"&gt;Foap&lt;/a&gt;, the company where our friend was working simply proposed us to work from their office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They lend us their meeting room. What can we say about their office? Just amazing. Big open space not crowded at all. Plus a kitchen, meeting rooms, ping pong table room and a huge room dedicated to thawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it's already time to say goodbye. For sure we'll come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Working from Foap office" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-03-11-poland/IMG_20150316_143328-996a1d2d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-ive-learned"&gt;What I've learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food. The food is so cheap and you have so much quantity in your plate. That's incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most important, I've learned that train is really slow in this country. So slow that in general it's indicated to prefer bus over trains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't hesitate to take express trains. These are not high speed train. They just stop to 5-8 stations instead of 20+. You're now warned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="l-blog-image--centered"&gt;&lt;img alt="Old man killing time in so slow Polish train" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-03-11-poland/IMG_20150313_110409-1cdc2983.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-next"&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a different journey from the first one. I liked to travel with a friend and visit another one on site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next trip may be closer. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Cecile Veneziani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First journey: London (26 Feb - 1 mar)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-02-26-london.html"/>
    <id>http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-02-26-london.html</id>
    <published>2015-02-26T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-19T12:42:08+02:00</updated>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So here I am. My journey begins with London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So here I am. My journey begins with London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-london"&gt;Why London?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="friends"&gt;Friends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://kevin.disneur.me/"&gt;Kevin, a Ruby on Rails developer&lt;/a&gt;, a good friend and ex-coworker moved there last September. He has invited me several times to come see him. So I taught it was logic to begin my journey by actually visiting him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="distance--transport"&gt;Distance / Transport&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London is close to Lille so I may have short commute time (in theory). The good news is that there are direct trains and buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="hosting"&gt;Hosting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally my friend and his wife invited me to share their home so I hadn't to look for a place to stay. Otherwise, I should have took time to look for a Couchsurfing host, Airbnb room or hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Look Right" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-02-26-london/IMG_20150226_175001-0b690db8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="days-in-london"&gt;4 days in London&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to equally split my time : 2 days of work and 2 days of visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-1-working-from-tymberyard"&gt;Day 1: Working from Tymberyard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to &lt;a href="https://tyuk.com/"&gt;Tymberyard cafe&lt;/a&gt;, had a nice quiche for lunch and worked there all the afternoon. Of course, I did respect the tea time habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my first cafe-working experience. It's pleasant to work among fifteen other cafe-workers and in a lovely place with a good playlist. This cafe is well situated, near Barbican station. No need to mention that it looks like the spirit of Shoreditch arrived in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tymberyard Café" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-02-26-london/IMG_20150226_142256-65172a6d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-2-working-from-work-hubs"&gt;Day 2: Working from @Work Hubs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a heavy user of a coworking space in Lille, I wanted to try one in London. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/philip_dodson"&gt;Philip Dodson&lt;/a&gt; welcomed me in his space &lt;a href="http://atworkhubs.co.uk/"&gt;@Work Hubs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a starter pass, chose a desk, had some ginger-lemon tea and started to work. The space is situated near Euston Square station. There are long desks, armchairs, free tea and biscuits and a small library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I also found there the first book from Hugh Laurie and bought it in favor of a non-profit organization. Had so much fun reading the adventures of Mr. Lang (The Gun Seller).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="@Work Hubs coworking space" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-02-26-london/IMG_20150227_143359-cb275531.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-3-4-visiting"&gt;Day 3-4: Visiting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to visit! Hung out with my friends, had a walk in parks and the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Visiting, Tower Bridge" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-02-26-london/IMG_20150228_153644-38b2e93c.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-ive-learned"&gt;What I've learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="high-prices"&gt;High prices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No big news here. London is an expensive city. If you go to London, you should make sure you have budget for oyster card credits, coworking space pass and food in cafés.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="transport"&gt;Transport&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned my travel 2 weeks ago. So the train rates weren't affordable anymore. Unsurprisingly, I took a bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long 6 hours ride including 30 minutes in a huge stainless can, on a train, in the depths of the sea. In fact it's not that terrible. We drove all the night so I just slept. OK, I had to take a nap before starting my first day work but that's it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="london-coworking-spaces"&gt;London coworking spaces&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaces referenced on coworking visa website don't exist anymore or don't propose hotdesking anymore. On top of that, hotdesking spaces are hard to find for a newcomer. It also seems that there is no non-profit coworking spaces in the center of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="London Rules" src="/assets/images/blog/articles/2015-02-26-london/IMG_20150301_103619-995dbf05.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-next"&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this first working-trip. I liked to live as a Londoner on weekdays and be a tourist on weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sure, I'll continue my journey in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Cecile Veneziani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Idea</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-01-08-the-idea.html"/>
    <id>http://nomadrides.com/blog/2015-01-08-the-idea.html</id>
    <published>2015-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-15T09:40:43+02:00</updated>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I'm a web developer, as a freelancer, I can work from any place that have a network connection.
Fine! This year I'll travel across Europe!
My goal is pretty simple: discover new places while working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I'm a web developer, as a freelancer, I can work from any place that have a network connection.
Fine! This year I'll travel across Europe!
My goal is pretty simple: discover new places while working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules are simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to a new place for 4 to 15 days (maximum)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book few days for work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the rest, just enjoy your journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-just-2-weeks"&gt;Why just 2 weeks?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't want to spend all my time traveling. I also like to be at home and enjoy my beautiful city (Lille, France). BUT, for now, I do want to visit a lot of cities.
So here is the deal: &lt;strong&gt;traveling on short period, traveling often&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Cecile Veneziani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
